Notes

While simple to implement, computation on a large dataset like ours took way too much time. Computation time is long because the model needs to compute distance of each query instance to all training samples. While K-D tree indexing was applied to mitigate this issue, it did not resolve the issue.

KNN models also suffer from normalization (bias towards category with most occurrences) and too many dimensions.

I also tried comparing KNN with DecisionTree and RandomForrest using gridsearch and getting f1 scores.